<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DATA>
<SCENE ID="1StartScene">
	<TEXT ID="1StartScene_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Point the mouse to each item in the picture to display its name. Click the “continue” button to start the experiment. The animation can be paused, reversed or moved forward at any point by using the controls at the upper right.</TEXTVALUE>
		</TEXT>
		</SCENE>
		<SCENE ID="1StartScene">
		
	<TEXT ID="1StartScene_two">
		<TEXTVALUE>Kundt’s tube apparatus- It is a simple acoustical apparatus which is used to measure the speed of sound through a gas or a solid rod.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>		
	</SCENE>
	
    
<SCENE ID="2TakeCorkPowder">
	<TEXT ID="2TakeCorkPowder_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Take the cork powder from the watch glass and put it uniformly on the ruler.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="3PutPowderonRuler">
	<TEXT ID="3PutPowderonRuler_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Take the cork powder from the watch glass and put it uniformly on the ruler.Take the ruler to the glass tube.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="4InsertRulerInToGlassTube">
	<TEXT ID="4InsertRulerInToGlassTube_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Tilt the ruler so that the cork powder falls uniformly in the glass tube. Remove the ruler from the tube, being careful not to disturb the uniformly spread powder.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="5TakeRuler">
	<TEXT ID="5TakeRuler_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Take the piston and insert it inside the glass tube.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="6TightTheMetalRodKnob">
	<TEXT ID="6TightTheMetalRodKnob_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Now adjust the clamp on the metal rod stand; tighten it to hold the metal rod exactly at its center.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="7InsertMetalRod">
	<TEXT ID="7InsertMetalRod_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Insert the metal rod into the glass tube.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="8TakeCloth">
	<TEXT ID="8TakeCloth_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Take the leather piece.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="9powdertake">
	<TEXT ID="9powdertake_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Take some rosin powder and put it in the leather.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="9powdderincloth">
	<TEXT ID="9powdderincloth_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Take some rosin powder and put it in the leather.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="10scrraching">
	<TEXT ID="10scrraching_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Hold the metal rod with the rosined leather and pull back.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>

<SCENE ID="11tighter">
	<TEXT ID="11tighter_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Longitudinal vibrations from rubbing the rod can be heard as sound; they cause the powder in the tube to get agitated.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>

<SCENE ID="12tubein">
	<TEXT ID="12tubein_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Adjust the length of the air column inside the glass tube by moving the piston in and out gently.Repeat the process till resonance is attained. At this position maximum sound can be heard.When resonance is attained, the powder will be collected as heaps inside the glass tube.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>

<SCENE ID="13scaler">
	<TEXT ID="13scaler_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>The number of heaps formed and the total length from the first to the last heap are recorded.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>


<SCENE ID="14result">
	<TEXT ID="14result_one">
		<TEXTVALUE>Then from the equations, knowing the speed of sound in air, the speed of sound in the rod can be calculated. If we know the density of the rod, we can also calculate its Young’s modulus.</TEXTVALUE>
	</TEXT>	
</SCENE>



</DATA>